yr.media 2019-03-31

# Privacy Policy - YR Media

Youth Radio’s privacy policy covers Youth Radio/Youth Media International and its websites. If you have an inquiry or concern about our privacy policy, please contact us below:

Youth Radio/Youth Media International  
1701 Broadway Oakland, CA 94612  
Websites(s): [www.youthradio.org](http://www.youthradio.org/), [www.alldayplay.fm](http://www.alldayplay.fm/), [www.bom411.com](http://www.bom411.com/), [www.youthradioeats.blogspot.com](http://www.youthradioeats.blogspot.com/), <http://turnstylenews.com/>

**What this Privacy and Security Policy Covers**

This policy covers Youth Radio/Youth Media International websites (from here forth referred to as Youth Radio) treatment of personally identifiable information that Youth Radio collects when you are on Youth Radio’s sites. Pursuant to Government Code Section 11019.9, all departments of Youth Radio of California shall enact and maintain a permanent privacy policy, in adherence with the Information Practices Act of 1977 (Civil Code Section 1798 et seq.), that includes, but not necessarily limited to the following principles:

1) Personally identifiable information may only be obtained through lawful means.

2) The purposes for which personally identifiable data are collected shall be specified at or prior to the time of collection, and any subsequent use of the data shall be limited to and consistent with the fulfillment of those purposes previously specified.

3) Personal data may not be disclosed, made available, or otherwise used for a purpose other than those specified, except with the consent of the subject of the data, or as required by law or regulation.

4) Personal data collected shall be relevant to the purpose for which it is needed.

5) The general means by which personal data is protected against loss, unauthorized access, use modification, or disclosure shall be posted, unless the disclosure of those general means would compromise legitimate agency objectives or law enforcement purposes.

**Youth Radio shall implement this privacy policy by:**

1) Designating a position within the agency to be responsible for the implementation of and adherence to this privacy policy;

2) Prominently posting the policy physically in its office and on its website (www.youthradio.org);

3) Distributing the policy to each of its third party partners who have access to personal data; Complying with the Information Practices Act (Civil Code Section 1798 et seq.), The Public Records Act (Government Code Section 6250 et seq.), Government Code Section 11015.5, and all other laws pertaining to information privacy laws; and

4) Using appropriate means to successfully implement and adhere to this privacy policy

**Information Collection and Use**

Youth Radio wants you to know about the collection, use, security, and access to information that may be obtained through use of Youth Radio’s web portals. By visiting this website, you are accepting the policies and practices described in this notice. Please note that this policy is subject to change at any time. This use policy is dated October 14, 2010.

This notice covers the following topics:

• Providing Visitors with Anonymous Access

• Personal Information and Choice

• A Special Note about Children

• What Happens to Information You Submit to Us

• Information Collected and How it is Used

• If You Send Us Email

• Donations

• Automatic Collection of Information/Cookies

• Security Access and Authorization Mechanisms

• Limitation of Liability

• Ownership

**Providing Visitors with Anonymous Access**

You can access our website home page and browse our pages anonymously without disclosing your personal data.

**Personal Information and Choice**

“Personal information” is information about a natural person that identifies or describes an individual, including, but not limited to, his or her name, social security number, physical description, home address, home telephone number, education, financial matters, and medical or employment history, readily identifiable to that specific individual. A domain name or Internet Protocol address is not considered personal information; however, it is considered “electronically collected personal information.”

According to Government Code Section 11015.5., “electronically collected personal information” means any information that is maintained by an organization that identifies or describes an individual user, including, but not limited to, his or her name, social security number, physical description, home address, home telephone number, education, financial matters, medical or employment history, password, electronic mail address, and information that reveals any network location or identity, but excludes any information manually submitted to an organization by a user, whether electronically or in written form, and information on or relating to individuals who are users, serving in a business capacity, including, but not limited to, business owners, officers, or principals of that business.

“Electronically collected personal information” that we automatically collect includes your domain name or Internet Protocol address, and statistical information about which web pages you visit. If you voluntarily participate in an activity that asks for specific information (i.e., sending an email, or participating in a survey) more detailed data will be collected; however, you can complete our survey or send us an email without disclosing your personal identity. If you choose to not give your name it will in no way affect your ability to use any feature of the website.

No person shall be discriminated against in participation of any Youth Radio’s programs or services because of race, color, age, religion, gender, sexual orientation, national origin or physical disability.

If any type of personal information is requested on the website or volunteered by the user, State law, including the Information Practices Act of 1977, Government Code Section 11015.5, and the federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it. However, this information may be a public record once you provide it, and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not otherwise protected by Federal or State law.

**A Special Note About Children (Minors)**

Minors (under age 18) are only eligible to participate in Youth Radio’s programs with consent from a legal guardian. If you are a minor, you can only participant in these programs only if you should seek permission from your legal guardian(s).

Youth Radio collects information from students for each of its programs. Before collecting personal information from minors, it will notify legal guardian(s) that it is being requested, disclose the reasons for collecting it, and disclose our intended use of it. Youth Radio will seek consent from legal guardian(s) before collecting any personally identifiable information. Legal guardian(s) may request information on the type of data being collected, view their child’s information, and, if they choose, prohibit Youth Radio from making further use of their child’s information. Youth Radio will not knowingly provide personal information about children to third parties.

The information we automatically collect or store is used to improve the content of our services and to help us understand how people are benefiting from our services. This information does not identify you personally and is used for gathering students’ statistics.

Government Code Section 11015.5.(a)(6) prohibits all agencies from distributing or selling any electronically collected personal information, as defined above, about users to any third party without the permission of the user. Youth Radio does not sell any “electronically collected personal information.” Any distribution of “electronically collected personal information” will be solely for the purposes for which it was provided to us.

**What Happens To Information You Submit To Us?**

If you choose to submit information to us, the information will be transmitted through secure lines to our departmental database. Any private information will only be used for the purposes for which it was provided and will not be shared with another entity except as prescribed by law. Please see our Privacy Policy for additional information.

**Information Collected And How It Is Used**

Youth Radio collects personal information directly from individuals who volunteer to use some of our services. Collection of this information is required to deliver the specific services, but use of these services is voluntary. If you do nothing during your visit to the website but browse or download information, we automatically collect and store the following information about your visit:

1) Which web pages or services you have accessed;

2) How you found our site;

3) Which search engines brought you to our site;

4) Which keywords you used on a search engine to bring you to your site;

5) The type of browser you used;

6) Which path you are taking through our site;

7) The website you visited prior to coming to this website;

8) The website you visit as you leave this website; and

9) If you downloaded a file or form, which file or form you downloaded

**If You Send Us Email**

You may choose to provide us with personal information, as in email with a comment or question. We use the information to improve our service to you or to respond to your request and will add you to our distribution list. Except for authorized law enforcement investigations or, as required by law, we do not share your email with any other organizations. You may also contact us at any time to be removed from our distribution list.

**Donations**

If you would like to support Youth Radio by providing a donation, we may request information from the user via Youth Radio’s link with Stripe who will process your online transaction. A user must provide contact information (like name, address) and financial information (like credit card number and expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes in order to complete your donation. If we have trouble processing a transaction, this contact information is used to get in touch with you.

When you donate to Youth Radio, you are placed on mailing lists for e-mail updates. If you do not wish to receive email from Youth Radio, please contact us. If you are making a donation in honor or memory of someone, we will not use their personal information for any purpose other than to send an acknowledgment card. Youth Radio does not make e-mail addresses available to any third-party for any reason.

**Automatic Collection of Information/Cookies**

Cookies are simple text files stored on your computer by your web browser (for information on cookies please see www.cookiecentral.com). We will not automatically log personal data nor do we link information automatically logged by other means with personal data about specific individuals.

We do not use cookies to store personal data nor do we link non-personal information stored in cookies with personal data about specific individuals.

Cookies created on your computer by using this website do not contain “personal information” and do not compromise your privacy or security. We use the cookie feature only to store a randomly generated identifying temporary tag on your computer. You can refuse the cookie or delete the cookie file from your computer by using any of the widely available methods. However, if you turn your cookie option off, you may not be able to access some of the features in our interactive applications.

**Ownership**

In general, information presented on Youth Radio’s website, unless otherwise indicated, is considered in the public domain. It may be distributed or copied as permitted by law. However, Youth Radio does make use of copyrighted data (e.g., photographs) which may require additional permissions prior to your use. In order to use any information on this website not owned or created by Youth Radio, you must seek permission directly from the owning (or holding sources). Youth Radio shall have the unlimited right to use for any purpose, free of any charge, all information submitted via this site except those submissions made under separate legal contract. Youth Radio shall be free to use, for any purpose, any ideas, concepts, or techniques contained in information provided through this site.

**Security Access and Authorization Mechanisms**

Youth Radio has taken several steps to safeguard the integrity of its telecommunications and computing infrastructure, including but not limited to verification, monitoring, access authorization mechanisms and password security to access the organization’s profiles. Youth Radio will not be held responsible for any misuse of passwords. Security measures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day practices of the entire Youth Radio environment as part of its continuing commitment to risk management. This information should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided via the Youth Radio supported website.

**Limitation of Liability**

Youth Radio attempts to maintain the highest accuracy of content on its website. Any errors or omissions should be reported for investigation.

Youth Radio makes no claims, promises, or guarantees about the absolute accuracy, completeness, or adequacy of the contents of this website and expressly disclaims liability for errors and omissions in the contents of this website. No warranty of any kind, implied, expressed, or statutory, including but not limited to the warranties of non-infringement of third party rights, title, merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose, and freedom from computer virus, is given with respect to the contents of this website or its hyperlinks to other Internet resources. Reference in this website to any specific commercial products, processes, or services, or the use of any trade, firm, or corporation name is for the information and convenience of the public, and does not constitute endorsement, recommendation, or favoring by Youth Radio, or its employees or agents.

This Use Policy is subject to change without notice.
